<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maths | Rishi</title>
    <link>https://rishidarkdevil.github.io/tag/maths/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://rishidarkdevil.github.io/tag/maths/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Maths</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://rishidarkdevil.github.io/media/icon_hucf31d7374fc459aedebb55d24d710d3c_248924_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Maths</title>
      <link>https://rishidarkdevil.github.io/tag/maths/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Musketeers in a Semicircle Problem</title>
      <link>https://rishidarkdevil.github.io/post/the-three-musketeers-in-a-semicircle-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rishidarkdevil.github.io/post/the-three-musketeers-in-a-semicircle-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across this interesting problem on which my seniors were brainstorming late at night. It requires a bit knowledge of continuous random variables in probability and little bit visualization capability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem goes like this… &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;There are three musketeers who stand on a circle randomly, which follows Uniform(0, 2πr) independently where r is the radius of the circle. They can help each other if they are close enough in case of a sudden attack by the enemies. Find the probability of them lying on the same semicircle.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read my detailed solution at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@rishidarkdevil/the-three-musketeers-in-a-semicircle-538677acc067&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Three Musketeers in a Semicircle Problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rabbit and the Stone Problem</title>
      <link>https://rishidarkdevil.github.io/post/the-rabbit-and-stone-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rishidarkdevil.github.io/post/the-rabbit-and-stone-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have this friend of mine, who constantly pokes me to solve interesting puzzles. He sometimes even rings me up, just to look at the problem he sent :P This is one of those problems, that I enjoyed working on. It requires understanding of basic probability theory, counting and some time to stick to a problem that interests you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem goes like this… &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;There are 7 stones in a row labelled 1 to 7 from left to right. A rabbit starts at stone 1 and on each turn hops to a new stone that they haven’t visited yet. After visiting all the stones, what is the probability the rabbit made exactly one leftwards jump?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read my detailed solution at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@rishidarkdevil/the-rabbit-and-the-stone-problem-90ff6c1d54e0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Rabbit And The Stone Problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Classic Urn Color Change Problem</title>
      <link>https://rishidarkdevil.github.io/post/the-classic-urn-color-change-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rishidarkdevil.github.io/post/the-classic-urn-color-change-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has taken probability class in their college or school is familiar with probability problems involving the classic urn (basically a bag) setup which contains balls of different colors and the professor asks you to find the probability of occurrence of some stupid pattern. This is one of those problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem goes like this… &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;You are given an urn with 100 balls (50 black and 50 white). You pick balls from urn one by one without replacements until all the balls are out. A black followed by a white or a white followed by a black is “a color change”. Calculate the expected number of color changes if the balls are being picked randomly from the urn.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read my detailed solution at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@rishidarkdevil/classic-urn-color-change-problem-c82a24aa549&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Classic Urn Color Change Problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
